[
 {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "1. What's the connection - 1? DEMONCRACY BY KADER ATTIA AND PLOTTING TABLE BY MONA HATOUM",
    "choices": ["Both artworks use light as a central element", "Both are by artists born in Iraq", "Both are guache and ink artworks"],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation": "Answer 1 Both artworks use light as a central element."
  },
   {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "2. What's the connection - 1? OPEN GATE AND TEMPIETTO IN ROME",
    "choices": ["Both are works painted by Youssef Kamel", "Both are works created by Farid Belkahia", "Both are works made in 1925"],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation": "Answer 2 They were both painted by Egyptian artist Youssef Kamel."
  },
   {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "3. What's the connection - 1? BIG BABA BY GHADEER SAEED AND SAMRY BY MOHAMMED AL KOUH",
    "choices": ["Both feature infants", "Both are monochromatic artworks", "Both use photography"],
    "correctAnswer": 3,
    "explanation": "Answer 3 Both artworks are photography-based."
  },
   {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "4. What's the connection - 1? MUNIRA AL KAZI AND ADEL AL KHALAF",
    "choices": ["Both are sculptures", "Both were born in Kuwait", "Both paint with their fingers instead of brushes"],
    "correctAnswer": 2,
    "explanation": "Answer 4 Al Kazi and Khalaf are both Kuwaiti nationals."
  },
   {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "5. What's the connection - 1? KHALED BEN SLIMANE’S ASCENSION XIII AND JAMIL HAMOUDI’S IF EVER FORGETFUL MENTION ALLAH",
    "choices": ["Both works incorporate Arabic calligraphy", "The artists are half-brothers", "Both feature the homelands of the artists"],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation": "Answer 5 Both artists make use of Arabic calligraphy in these works."
  },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "6. What's the connection - 1? EBTISAM ABDULAZIZ AND HASSAN SHARIF",
    "choices": ["Both were students of Mohammed Kazem", "Both are founders of the Fine Art Society", "Both have used performance as a medium"],
    "correctAnswer": 3,
    "explanation": "Answer 6 Both of these Emirati artists has used performance in their art practice."
  },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "7. What's the connection - 1? SEATED MUSICIAN BY SAMIR RAFI AND WOMAN SEWING BY LOUAY KAYYALI",
    "choices": ["Both helped define a new style called Primacolor", "Both were in the exhibition RE: Orient", "Both are large murals"],
    "explanation": "Answer 7 Both artworks were part of Barjeel's 2014 exhibit RE: Orient."
  },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "8. What's the connection - 1? STEVE SABELLA’S PIECE METAMORPHOSIS AND ASIM ABU SHAKRA’S PIECE CACTUS",
    "choices": ["Both artworks depict a cactus in a window", "Both are oil on canvas paintings", "Both were made after the year 2000"],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation": "Answer 8 Both artworks feature a cactus in a window."
  },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "9. What's the connection - 1? THE WORK OF ARTISTS THURAYA AL BAQSAMI AND NASSER AL YOUSIF",
    "choices": ["Both are most famous for their sculptures", "Both are well known for using a lino-cut print technique ", "Both are known for geometric compositions"],
    "correctAnswer": 2,
    "explanation": "Answer 9 Al Baqsami and Al Yousif are well known for using a lino-cut print technique."
  },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "10. What's the connection - 1? SALIBA DOUAIHY’S WORK AND JAFAR ISLAH’S PIECE “COLOURS WITH BLACK AND GREY",
    "choices": ["Both feature modern Gulf architecture", "employ bold colours and geometric shapes  ", "Both represent landscapes of Aleppo"],
    "correctAnswer": 2,
    "explanation": "Answer 10 Each employs bold colours and geometric shapes."
  }
]  
